These are the funniest animal videos ever
He looks so cute. Oh my god
Are you still here go away
I need an egg. Thank you
These people were lost and stopped to ask for directions
Good afternoon, excuse me, to Bologna, to Josefina
That's good, man
If you eat in my car, maybe there's something dead on it
Oh
This sheep was stuck in a trench and got rescued
Thank you for being so patient
You've been so patient
Okay now
This poor little hedgehog deflated
These girls found a squirrel on the side of the road that they thought could use some help
Oh my god
This person tried picking up a frog
One, two, three
You did know that
How are you?
My
Amazing
Merv
Eti
고양
Hey, you almost done?
Hey! You almost done?
It's Horace! Horace, no, that won't go in your cheek!
Come here, no, no, pass me the...
The streamer was trying to sneak up on this deer without scaring it.
A zoo installed a new security camera and it scared the snow leopard.
He's like, oh there's a camera on me.
Yeah, what up everybody!
Oh, I see how it is.
Rude.
So this is really interesting and I have no explanation for why,
but this frog refuses to jump outside of this circle.
Yeah, see?
Oh my god!
Nah, that's the maddest, bro.
Bro?
That's sick!
He's gonna put it on, bro?
Nah, he's not gonna put it on.
Bro, he's gonna put it on, bro.
Nah!
Come on, guys!
Ah!
for some reason this horse doesn't like talking to men no boys right especially not this one
he made a fire to warm up his horses that were in the field for the horses here and
uh and uh this this one might have got a little close these two little guys were spotted doing
push-ups at the gym this gorilla was upset that their stick got stuck
oh no
mashallah
are you kidding me
poor guy got so upset
well hi there are you good or are you bad
bad i'm not sure if this cat is really brave or really dumb
this poor pelican suddenly fell asleep
they will look he just has to yeah
oh my god oh my god
oh my god
hey
where are you going
this cat was chasing a mouse and couldn't figure out where it went
where's the mouse
the towel
i'm trying to
i guess you never know when squirrels might attack
this pigeon was walking around and intentionally put on some bread necklaces
oh my god
this llama
this llama heard someone make a rude comment
oh
he's ugly
that's cute
damn
did i say something
oh
i'm in
I think we found out who the main character is.
She kept being harassed by her horse so she decided to finally catch him in the act.
Say cheese! Cheese!
This groundhog keeps stealing food from this farmer and always eats it directly in front of the security camera.
These otters were spotted chasing a butterfly.
I think this fish is broken.
Sometimes an octopus will try and punch a fish just for fun.
This is a hognose snake which is a harmless snake that likes to play dead.
Play dead.
For some reason, this cow was trying to catch its own tail.
I have never seen this type of disrespect before.
I have never seen it before.
Okay.
For some reason, this hamster has a knife.
Why is this capybara so small?
This truck that was carrying oranges broke down so these elephants took advantage.
These guys have got a bit of a problem here.
And the elephants are coming and helping themselves, taking advantage.
These eagles were trying to build a nest together.
Oh my god.
He's done with asking and has started demanding.
This guy found a really round bear.
He is a fat bear.
Oh my god.
The Gina bear.
He is so chunky.
There's a lot more over here on this left side.
This duck loves getting kisses.
A cat is so glibbara.
He is so glibbara.
Have you ever seen a horse that's equipped with turbo?
This pigeon was hurt so they spent months nursing it back to full health.
They were finally ready to release it back into the wild.
I can't tell which bird is more angry.
This poor little guy doesn't know how wheels work.
This fish somehow found a pacifier.
This little baby chicken was adopted by this duck.
This ostrich kept bothering this giraffe.
I don't think the ostrich was supposed to be there.
This monkey was really excited to see her.
Good morning Nick!
Yeah!
Good morning!
This poor little guy couldn't hold on.
This monkey was really excited to see her.
Good morning Nick!
Yeah!
Good morning!
This poor little guy couldn't hold on.
This monkey was really excited to see her.
Good morning Nick!
Yeah!
Good morning!
This poor little guy couldn't hold on.
This small dog doesn't know where to help.
My finger was ready to step up as nothing is better.
He created aieron summer but he came up.
During my small onions while raising the
room within each boy下面.
This penguin wasn't having a very good day after falling in some mud.
This cat somehow managed to scare away a bear.
They couldn't figure out why their car wasn't starting.
It's just like that.
Now my M4 just got jacked.
I'm trying to go to sleep or take a nap and he's just...
It seems like this bird is trying to be as annoying as possible.
So why is he sitting like this?
This lion was chasing a wildebeest when the unexpected happened.
This lion was chasing a wildebeest.
Someone found a bird that wants to take over the world.
He really decided that violence was the only option.
This deer loves eating bananas.
These two fish really don't like each other.
What the heck is going on here?
I told you, you have to stop coming around.
Stop bringing your mates.
I can see he's there.
We have no food.
A fisherman caught a fish and then tried to release it but it wouldn't swim back down.
This is because there was air in the gas bladder of the fish.
The fisherman helped the fish burp to release the air.
Burp it out.
Oh my god.
What's going on here?
Bro.
What the what?
I told you, you have to stop coming around.
Stop bringing your mates.
I can see he's there.
We have no food.
A fisherman caught a fish and then tried to release it but it wouldn't swim back down.
This is because there was air in the gas bladder of the fish.
The fisherman helped the fish burp to release the air.
Is that better?
Now let's see.
Oh look at that.
Away he goes.
Chase me, chase me, chase me, chase me, chase me.
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
Let's go, let's go.
These raccoons were caught in the act.
The turtle.
The turtle is like.
The turtle is lying.
The Ohio Leader.
That is the end of this video, we hope you enjoyed.
That is the end of this video, I hope you enjoyed, and I'll see you guys again very, very soon.
Later!