What about me? This is murder.
What about Scotland Yard?
What about Sherlock Holmes?
Now get out!
Did you get it?
Good.
Did you have any
trouble with him?
Just a matter of murder.
- Ah, Mr. Holmes.
- Hopkins.
Thanks for coming so promptly.
Inspector Lestrade suggested
that I call through to you.
- Mr. Emery was a client of Mr. Holmes, Inspector.
- Indeed.
You didn't mention that when
I telephoned you, Mr. Holmes.
Well not exactly
a client, Inspector.
- Sergeant Thompson?
- He was killed between the hours of eleven
and two o'clock this
morning, Mr. Holmes.
Must have been someone he knew.
Someone of whom
he had no suspicion.
Poor old Stinky.
It's all my fault.
I should have prevented this.
Well, it's no time to start
talking about that now, Doctor.
Apparently, it's gone.
That's the second attempt
on the musical box
that Emery bought
at the auction sale
and this time it was successful.
But that box is only
worth two pounds.
It's worth a man's life, Watson.
I think we'd better pay a visit to Gaylord's
Auction Room and that fellow Crabtree.
Inspector may I suggest
that you make a complete
search of this flat
for a small plain musical
box about that size.
Thank you. Come on, Watson.
You say the first box
went to Mr. Julian Emery,
the second, Mr. Kilgour,
143B Hampton Way,
and the third to the
unidentified young lady
who presumably has a shop
and lives near Golders Green?
That's right Mr. Holmes.
Isn't it rather strange,
Mr. Crabtree,
that you've had three identical musical
boxes, all playing the same tune?
- Where did they come from?
- Dartmoor Prison.
- Dartmoor?
- We get a regular shipment from there every month.
The inmates manufacture them.
Well, they make all kinds
of things you know?
Pipe racks, wastepaper baskets,
- musical boxes.
- Did you happen to notice
if anyone showed any particular
interest during the auction
in the purchases
of these three boxes?
Oh, come now, Mr. Crabtree,
this is very literally a
matter of life and death.
Well, since you put it
that way, Mr. Holmes,
there was a gentleman came in here
about an hour after closing time.
And he was in an
awful state, he was,
he gave me five pounds to tell
him where the boxes had gone.
He said they had sentimental
value for him, sir.
Expensive sentiment.
Can you describe him?
Well he was tall,
distinguished looking
and he had gray hair
and a mustache.
He was quite a gentleman, sir.
And what was his reaction
when you were
unable to supply him
with the address of the young
lady who owned the shop?
I told him that the young lady
usually come back on Thursday.
He said he'd come back on
Thursday and that's tomorrow.
Thank you Mr. Crabtree, you've
been very helpful. Thank you.
Come along, Watson.
- Where we going now, Holmes?
- The home of Mr. Kilgour,
the man who bought
the third box.
But hang it all, Holmes,
how do you know those other two
musical boxes are of any importance?
I don't, but I certainly
have no intention
of waiting till the owners
are murdered to find out.
No one at home.
I hope that's the explanation.
Well, have a look
through this window.
Doesn't seem to be anyone there.
Whole place seems deserted
as far as I can see.
- Yes?
- Mr. and Mrs. Kilgour at home?
- No.
- When do you expect them?
Oh, in an hour or so.
There's no use
you're hanging about.
They don't buy nothing
from peddlers.
Peddlers?
My good woman this is
Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
Sherlock Holmes? Oh, go on.
Do you mind if we
come in and wait?
My business is rather urgent.
Well, I've got to go out
to do my shopping
and I don't know if Mrs. Kilgour
would like any strangers
nosing about.
Quite all right, I assure you.
Well, I've got to be off.
You two wait in the parlor
and no smoking either.
Mrs. Kilgour says it
smells up the house.
- Funny old girl, Holmes.
- Hmm.
- Park Lane.
- Park Lane?
And what would the likes of
you be doing in Park Lane?
Now don't worry
about the fare, ducky.
If ya knows how to get
to Park Lane, now off it.
You know, Holmes,
I've been thinking.
There must have been
something hidden
in that box of old Stinky's.
Stolen jewelry possibly.
- What's up Holmes?
- Listen.
Well, it's just the steam
in the water pipes.
Watson!
Great Scott!
Come along, Holmes,
get her on the chair here.
Shh. It's all right, my dear.
There, there, there.
Now don't worry.
It's all over.
There you are, dear.
Don't cry anymore.
She tied me up and
shut me in the cupboard.
I know, I know.
She won't come back.
Did you show her
your new musical box?
Yes. She said she
wanted to hear it play
- and as soon as I showed it to her she grabbed a hold...
- I know. I know now.
Now don't worry, we'll buy
you a new musical box.
Yes, my dear,
the best one in London.
Watson.
Oh, what a fool,
what a fool I've been.
What do you mean, Holmes?
She took the musical box
out of this house
in that market basket
right under our very noses.
Why would the Kilgour charwoman
want to take the music box?
She isn't the Kilgour charwoman
she's a consummate actress.
An extremely clever, unscrupulous
woman who will stop at nothing.
Take care of the child,
will you, old fellow,
till her parents get back.
- Explain everything to them.
- Of course I will.
But Holmes, where are you going?
Somewhere, somehow
I must get to the young lady who
bought that third musical box
before our opponents find her.
I only hope that
I won't be too late.
Now, now, now, darling
you mustn't cry anymore.
Cheer up.
Would you... would you
like to hear old uncle
make a noise like a duck?
Oh, sorry. Huh.
Now, ladies and gentlemen
how much am I offered
for this beautiful laced
Dresden china figurine?
A lady of the French court.
Now this is the genuine article.
What a beautiful ornament
for your mantelpiece
as a centerpiece on
the dining room table.
Now will somebody
start me for ten pounds?
Will somebody start me
for ten pounds?
Eight pounds?
Seven pounds?
All right five.
Five pounds is offered.
Five pounds ten.
Five pounds fifteen,
five pounds fifteen.
Six pounds is offered.
Six pounds, six pounds,
going once, going twice,
the third and the last call
we're all done.
Sold to the lady from
Trikland for six pounds.