shucks, ellen. i knew ohm's law
before they even passed it.
well, i don't want pidge
to miss the ball game,
after missing the movie
and everything.
all right, boy. come on,
get ready to plug this set in
while i hold this screw down,
we'll see what happens.
ok.
dad, are you sure
you know what you're doing?
ellen, please.
i know, but it says
on the back of that
that there're 5,000 volts,
and that's dangerous.
ellen, will you please
stop being a woman?
ready, boy? plug in.
dad! dad,
are you all right?
well, i guess i'm all right.
it just scared the pants off me,
that's all.
golly! look at this!
i guess maybe
you'd better call jud, huh?
oh, honestly.
that was a close call, boy.
how much is 5,000 volts?
enough.
to kill you?
well, it'd probably pick you up
and toss you across the room.
that is, unless you were
standing in a puddle of water,
and then you'd be grounded.
and if you were grounded, it'd
kill you deader than a doornail.
would it hurt?
like blazes!
you stay away
from that set, now,
and stay away
from those wall plugs.
don't monkey with electricity
unless you know
what you're doing.
why did you, grandpa?
you got me there, boy.
i'll get it.
jud says he'll be up
in a little while.
i'm sorry.
honestly!
yes?
mrs. benson?
that's right.
is your husband at home?
my hus--no, i'm a widow.
what i should have asked was,
are you the owner of this house?
well, no, i'm not, it belongs
to my father-in-law.
what is it you want?
i'm john baron, special agent.
federal bureau of investigation.
these are my men.
do you suppose i could have
a few words with mr. benson?
well, just a moment.
won't you come in?
dad!
oh, how are you, gents?
john baron, special agent.
for heaven's sake! f.b.i.
may we come in?
why, sure, sure!
come right in. come right in.
make yourselves at home.
thanks.
not at all.
i get quite a kick out of this.
used to be with the treasury
department myself.
really?
back in the old days.
collector of
internal revenue, eh?
tax collector? not on your life.
secret service.
you don't say.
grandpa was president coolidge's
bodyguard.
you don't say.
yep. back in 1928.
youngest retirement
in the service.
account of my heart. not
heart trouble, you understand.
an accident on
one of cal's fishing trips.
a hunter.
got the slug right here.
say, that's a nasty one.
how come you're still alive?
pop: i don't know.
lodged in my heart.
they took it out. had to take it
easy, so they retired me.
man: you're lucky.
luckier still
if it hadn't hit me.
i want to be in
the secret service someday.
thought you was going
to be a sheriff like tod.
squirts like you are supposed
to grow up and be president.
name's pidge, mr. baron.
glad to meet you, pidge.
i ain't a squirt.
mr. baron, what did
you want to see us about?
is something wrong?
nothing wrong yet, mrs. benson.
but there might be.
we're just checking.
on us?
on the house.
do you mind if we have
a look around?
help yourself,
but what i want to know--
we're going to have
a look around
with or without your permission,
mr. benson.
it's an emergency.
check it.
there must be
something the matter.
anyone else live here,
besides you three?
ellen: no.
anyone been by here today?
just the usual routine.
willy harris left the milk.
what's this all about,
mr. baron?
just being careful.
i'll explain later.
two bedrooms,
one bathroom. all clear.
one here. just like they said.
kitchen, back pantry,
back door,
stairs go downhill
to garage under kitchen.
cellar door in hall. clear.
car in the garage.
look at this for a set-up.
i'm sorry, folks, but i'm afraid
we're going to have
to hang around for a while.
why?
what's the matter?
don't be alarmed.
there's nothing wrong.
well, course
there's something wrong.
the f.b.i. doesn't pay us
a visit for the heck of it.
well, i won't stay.
i'll take pidge and go--
no, ma'am.
nobody leaves the house
until we do.
why not? what's happened?
look, just go about
your business
like it was any other
saturday afternoon.
read your papers
and look at your t.v.
anything you want.
but nobody leaves the house.
something fishy about all this.
it's official business.
what sort of official business?
mr. benson.
as a former agent
of the secret service,
you should understand.
either i'm getting
old and stupid,
or else i'm--
at five p.m. this afternoon,
the president of the united
states arrives in town
on a special.
what?
golly!
the president?
well, that's different.
do you mean to say
the president's
going to get off the train here?
that's right.
golly, gramps.
we gotta go down and see it,
we just gotta.
the president! why,
that's the greatest thing
ever happened to this town!
can we go down and see it,
gramps? can we?
sorry, kid. no.
benny, bring in the gear.
put the car out back.
bart, you see
the back door's locked tight
and check the cellar to be sure.
i still don't understand--
mr. benson.
it should be obvious
to you that
if anybody wanted
to kill the president,
he could do
a beautiful job of it
right from this window of yours.
for the love of mike!
that may be true,
but you don't think
that ellie and me--
of course not.
but we have to remain here
to protect you
and the president
from somebody else who might.
oh.
carney.
yeah.
uh, is this all routine?
it seems to me
to be kind of overboard.
i mean, all this checking
and everything,
as though
you expected this town to--
sheriff. have you noticed
any strangers in town
during the past week?
no.
are you sure?
sure i'm sure.
i know everybody in this burg.
the only strangers
we get are tourists,
you know,
and we get 'em all the time,
stopping for gas,
a bite to eat, that's all.
we want to know from
either you or your deputies
the minute any stranger
doesn't keep going through.
then this isn't routine.
no, it isn't.
can you tell me?
the los angeles police picked up
a small-time stool pigeon
night before last.
shot through the lungs
and left for dead.
smiley bitters. before he died,
he told them something was up.
what do you mean,
something was up?
an assassination attempt.
well, can you believe that?
in our business,
we can't afford not to.
i mean, the tip
of a dying stool pigeon.
the stoolie seemed
very proud of being an american,
before he kicked off.
meaning crime is crime, but
this is something else again?
right. so, we can't take
any chances. let's go.
can we see the president,
grandpa?
mm-mm.
can we, mom?
no, pidge, we have to stay here.
you can watch him from here.
but i wanna get up close.
well, use your telescope, boy.
bring him right up to your eye.
aww!
sorry, pidge. no dice.
back door locked. how about
the phone in the kitchen?
want me to yank it?
no, we don't change the pattern
at all. give benny a hand.
mr. baron, uh, something
i don't understand.
i was in the service myself--
so you told me.
and though we made
every precautionary check,
we never went
to extremes like this unless--
unless you were tipped that
there was to be
an attempted assassination.
well, you don't mean it.
i mean it.
but you're f.b.i.
secret service is responsible
for the safety of the president.
we're using everybody this trip,
mr. benson.
have a look down there.
state troopers, your local law
enforcement agencies and us.
you don't know if old dan carney
is down there, do you?
he and i worked together
in the old days.
he's chief of
the presidential staff now.
that's confidential
information.
this is a terrible thing.
not your worry, mr. benson.
of course it's my worry.
i'm an american, ain't i?
it's everybody's worry.
car. somebody's driving up
to the house.
who is it?
pidge: it's tod!
ellen: he's the sheriff,
mr. baron.