(speaking Chinese)
Oh Su Lin, we've been looking
for you all these weeks.
Mr. Williams needs your
help so desperately.
I cannot help.
You must forget that you found Su Lin.
Forget it?
But you're his only witness!
You're the only one that can help!
Not as a witness, only with silence
can I repay
his great kindness to me
and my family in China.
Why?
I heard other things
that most unhappy day
from Mrs. Williams' bedroom.
His voice very loud and angry.
A flower bases broken to pieces.
He can explain all that.
They do not believe
what he's already told,
that I heard anything would
do harm. Don't you see?
Yes.
Much sorrow comes from women
who know not honor and truth.
And Mrs. Williams, she's not true.
Even to that Torrence man.
What makes you say that?
That night when he was
killed, her sickness was but
wall of falsehood behind
which she could go secretly
to a meeting place.
You... you mean
she went out that night?
Su Lin, are you sure?
Yes, because next morning
in her bedroom
I found street shoes
that had been worn.
Her coat on the closet
floor with the sleeves
turned inside out
as though removed hurriedly,
and in one pocket a door key
to some hotel.
Su Lin! That's it!
Proof that she and Torrence
had planned to meet that night
after he killed Mr. Williams.
What hotel was it?
Oh, I... I don't remember.
The key, what did you do with it?
Returned to coat pocket.
Come on,
we'll get to Lieutenant Quincy.
He'll know what to do.
And pray, Su Lin,
every step of the way.
Now hold everything.
Even if this long shot don't work out,
we'll just keep on pitching.
(speaking Chinese)
Here it is. Yes.
Room 302. Airport Hotel, Oakland.
Maybe we got our miracle!
A special little Chinese one.
It is the hope that
Su Lin was a small help
to Mr. William.
Oh, Su Lin!
Come on. Next stop, Oakland.
I sense a little ladies
Hotel Rendezvous.
I was on night duty then,
all right.
But I sure don't remember
a looker like this.
Quite a dish, eh?
A little two highly seasoned
for my digestion, thanks.
Lieutenant.
Just found a couple of cards
for room 302 on June 9th.
Judge Baxter checked out at noon.
Mr. And Mrs. J Burns.
Room not slept in.
J Burns, Burns.
Look Quincy, the handwriting
on the card is identical
to that on the photograph.
And here's a little
more of the same thing.
The coverup telegram to Aunt Margaret.
And look at the impressions.
Jay here and here, RNS.
J Burns, that's the name
she started a telegram too.
Room not slept in.
Say I got that dame
pegged now, Lieutenant,
she said they'd be out
of the room by midnight
as her husband was catching a plane.
But Quincy,
this ties it all up, doesn't it?
Yeah, like a greased pig.
What do you mean? We've got
the evidence now, the proof.
Of what?
Su Lin's theory that Irene
was playing the field?
This evidence only proves
that she came here
to keep a date
with a man named Burns.
We can't even prove that
he didn't keep the date.
But you know he didn't,
there wasn't any Burns.
It was only a name that
she and Torrence used!
Fine, if you can prove that
Williams will be free, but
none of this will prove it.
Sorry copper, but we are
just up another blind alley.
-Wait!
-Yes sir?
There's a couple of sample
cases from Mr. Sam Andrews.
Came up from the station this morning.
Take them to Parlor B right away.
Sure thing, sir.
(bangs gavel)
Be seated.
Case of the state
versus Walter Williams.
Proceed, Mr. Eldridge.
Your Honor, we will
call Mrs. Irene Williams.
Take the stand Mrs. Williams.
Raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear the
testimony you're about
to give in this cause to be
the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
I do.
-What cooks?
-The defense call on her?
Mr. Eldridge, what's the
purpose in calling this witness?
Merely for purposes of
identifying handwriting.
Now, Mrs. Williams, this
photograph of you...
Was stolen from my apartment.
So, according to the inscription,
"to Walt, my adoring and
adored husband, Irene,"
this belongs to Mr. Williams.
This is your handwriting, isn't it?
Of course.
I'm touched that he should
have wanted it so badly.
And this telegram addressed
to Mrs. Margaret Hubbard.
Is that also your handwriting?
It is.
Now Mrs. Burns, I mean, Mrs. Williams,
This photograph is inscribed,
"to Jim, my adoring and adored, Irene."
Did you write this too?
I... I see no point in all this.
Merely answer counsel's questions.
-Did you write it?
-I did.
And these letters addressed
to Mr. James Torrence...
-did you write them?
-Yes.
And this monogrammed garment,
a gift from you to Mr. Torrence?
Why must I be tortured
again by all this?
I never made any secret of
my love for Jim Torrence.
That's why he is dead.
Your love for Jim Torrance?
Yet on the very night he was killed,
you had a rendezvous with a
man named Burns, didn't you?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I don't know any man named Burns.
I was at home that night, very ill.
Oh yes, the sleeping pills.
Well, you must walk
in your sleep then,
for you spent at least
part of that night
at the airport hotel in Oakland,
where you registered for
Mr. and Mrs. J Burns.
Don't waste the court's time
trying to deny it.
This is the registration card
that you signed at 9:20 PM,
and there's the room clerk
who assigned you to room 302.
And this Mrs. Williams
is the key to room 302,
which you very carelessly
left in the pocket of a coat,
which was found
in your closet yesterday.
All right. I was there.
Now are you satisfied?
Not quite.
This Jay Burns, Mrs. Williams.
Was his first name Jack?
Yes.
Have you been in
contact with him lately?
No. No!
How long since you
have seen or heard
from this Jack Burns?
Well, I don't know.
I don't remember!
You bet she doesn't remember,
because there isn't any Jack
Burns and there never was.
That was an alias for Jim Torrence,
and it was Torrence who was
to have met you that night
after your charming little
plot to kill your husband
had been duly executed.
It's not true! It's not true!
I have bad news
for you, Mrs. Williams.
I can prove it's true.
These pajamas, these
letters, this picture,
all of which you
identified for the court,
were found in this suitcase,
which is full of the clothes
and personal belongings
of Mr. James Torrence.
And the suitcase was
found in the baggage room
of the airport hotel, where
it's been held since June 9th,
and it says on this tag,
in large print, "hold for Jack Burns."