Sure, sure, hanging around
like a duck in a shooting gallery.
From the skylight, but
how did he reach the ground?
- I'm pretending there ain't any Earl.
- He could have jumped to this roof.
From the roof he could slide
down the drainpipe.
And come in any of these windows.
If the story walks in the window...
Masterminds. Why don't you go home?
Maybe Williams will call on you.
It'd be funny if he was
in this building.
Why not search the building?
- I am not wandering all over.
- A great bunch of reporters you are.
Too lazy to go after
the biggest story in years.
You seem pretty anxious
to get rid of us.
- Are you trying to scoop us?
- Are you crazy? On my time?
Maybe Mollie's been giving her
the truth on how Williams got the gun.
I didn't do nothing.
- Come clean.
- Let the girl alone. She's...
Well?
Mrs. Baldwin. Mother.
Don't "mother" me. Playing cat and
mouse and keeping my boy locked up.
Making us miss two trains, and you
supposed to be married tomorrow.
- I'll be with you in five minutes...
- Just give me Bruce's money.
You can stay here forever,
you and that murderer you caught.
- Murderer?
- Which one of these men is it?
- They all look like murderers.
- What murderer did you catch?
I never said any such thing.
I'm quoting my son.
He has never lied to me.
Somebody's lying.
- I never said anything like that.
- Yes, you did.
I said I was trying
to find the murderer.
- Quit stalling.
- She's got it balled up.
Who are you holding out on?
Nobody. Now let me go, will you?
Stop it, stop it!
She don't know where he is.
I'm the only one that knows.
- Where's Williams?
- Try and find out.
- Come on, talk.
- Now you want me to talk?
- Talk.
- Ain't that funny?
You wouldn't listen to me before,
and now you want me to talk.
Don't say anything.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Stay out of this.
- Why didn't you listen to me?
- Cut that out.
- Hands off!
- Where is he?
Why do you want to know? So you can
write more lies to sell papers?
- Never mind that.
- All right. I'll give you a story.
A wonderful story!
Only this time it'll be true.
You'll never find me now!
Get the ambulance, somebody!
Get an ambulance, somebody!
- She's dead.
- No, she isn't killed, she's moving!
- Did you see that? She jumped.
- I know that.
Where have you got Williams?
Hidden. He's in the desk.
She didn't kill herself.
- How're you doing?
- Let me out.
Quiet. You're sitting pretty.
- What's in there?
- Who are you?
- This is Bruce's mother.
- What are you doing?
- Shut up!
- You're doing something wrong.
- Mother, please.
- Take her out of here.
- Take the lady to Polack Mike's.
- My name's Louie Peluso.
See that she doesn't talk to anyone.
Tell them it's a case of D.T.'s.
Don't worry, Mother.
It's only temporary.
Let go of me.
- Where are you going?
- To get Bruce out of jail.
- Why did you do this to me?
- Get Bruce out of jail?
How can you worry about a man
who's resting in a police station?
- This is war! You can't desert me.
- Get off that trapeze.
You've got your story.
"Earl Williams captured
by the Morning Post".
I covered your story for you,
now I'm getting out.
You drooling idiot, there are 365 days
in a year one can get married.
How many times you got a murderer
locked up in a desk?
You got the whole city
by the seat of the pants.
You've got the brain of a pancake.
This isn't just a story.
It's a revolution.
The greatest yarn since
Livingston discovered Stanley.
- The other way around.
- Don't get technical at such a time.
You've taken a city that's been
graft-ridden for 40 years...
...and given us a chance to have
the same kind of government...
...New York has under La Guardia.
If I didn't have your best interest
at heart, I wouldn't argue with you.
You've done something big.
You've stepped up into a new class.
We'll make such monkeys of those
ward healers nobody'll vote for them.
- Expose them?
- We'll crucify that mob.
We'll keep Williams under cover,
until we can break the story...
...then share the glory
with the governor.
- I get it, I get it.
- You'll kick over City Hall.
You got the mayor and Hartwell
backed up against the wall.
This isn't just a newspaper story.
It's a career!
And you bellyache about catching
the eight or nine o'clock train.
- But I never figured it that way.
- Because you're a doll-faced hick.
They'll be naming streets after you.
There'll be statues of you.
The movies will be after you.
There'll be a Hildy Johnson cigar.
I can see the billboards now:
"Light up with Hildy Johnson..."
- We got a lot to do.
- Now you're talking.
- We can't leave Williams here.
- We'll take him to my private office.
- How are you going to take him?
- We'll carry the desk over.
It's crawling with cops outside.
We'll lower it out
the window with pulleys.
Start pounding out a lead!
- How much of this stuff do you want?
- All you the words you got.
- Can I call the mayor a bird of prey?
- Call him anything you like.
Give him the works. Hello, Duffy?
We got the biggest story in years.
"Earl Williams captured by
the Morning Post. Exclusive!"
Tear out the whole front page.
The whole front page. Out!
And never mind the European war.
We got something bigger than that.
Hildy Johnson's writing the lead.
And get hold of Butch O'Connor.
Tell him to come up here
with his wrestlers.
Yeah, Butch O'Connor.
What? I've got a desk
I want moved...
What the deuce do you want?
- Hello, Bruce.
- Hildy.
Never mind the Chinese earthquake.
- I just want to ask you...
- How'd you get out of jail?
Not through any help of yours.
I'm not talking to you.
I had to wire Albany for $100
so I could get out on bail.
What will they think in Albany?
The money went to the police station.
- We're waiting for that story.
- We'll explain everything to them.
- Where's mother?
- She left.
I can't hear you.
- Where'd she go?
- Out someplace.
- Junk the Polish Corridor!
- Tell me where my mother was going.
- She couldn't say.
- This is more important.
- Did she get the money?
- She left in a hurry.
- I'll take that money.
- In my purse.
I can handle things.
I'll take that certified check too.
I'll give you the tickets.
You'll find your money in the wallet.
My wallet? This is my wallet.
Say, there's something funny going on...
What are you doing?
Just wanted to look at it.
Hildy, I'm taking...
- I'm taking the 9 o'clock train.
- Sure, sure.
Did you hear what I said?
I said I am taking the 9 o'clock...
Oh, Bruce, I put it in here!
Let her alone, will you, buddy.
- Do me a favor...
- Just answer one question.
You don't want to come
with me, do you?
Answer me.
You don't, do you?
No. Take the Miss America
pictures off page six.
Hildy, tell me.
Tell me the truth.
Wait a minute.
Now look here, my good man...
You shut up, Burns.
You're doing all this to her.
She wanted to get away from you.
But you caught her
and changed her mind...
Stick Hitler on the funny page.
Now let me ask you...
Will you give up everything
for a man like him?
No, but something's happened.
I'll tell you...
Tell him nothing.
He's a spy, you fool.
- I am not a spy.
- Ridiculous.
You're coming with me right now.
Just a second. This is the
biggest thing in my life.
I see. I'll keep.
I'm like something in the icebox.
You just don't love me.
That isn't true. Just because you
won't listen you say I don't love you.
You never intended to be decent
and live like a human being.
All right, if that's what
you want to think.
I'm trying to concentrate.
- You're just like him and all the rest.
- Sure. That's what I am.
What? Leave the rooster story alone.
That's human interest.
If you had any sympathy
or understanding...
- I understand, all right...
- Wait a minute.
There's one question I want to know.
The mayor's first wife's name.
The one with the wart on her? Fanny.
What, Duffy?
You never loved me at all.
Never mind.
You don't work for advertising.
If you change your mind,
I'm on the 9 o'clock train.
If you want me, take me as I am.
Don't try to change me.
I'm no suburban bridge player.
I'm a newspaperman.
That's it. Keep it coming
as fast as you can.
Get back in there, you mock turtle.
You tell Butch it's a matter
of life and death?